creativemarket.com 2019-06-24

# Privacy Policy ~ Creative Market

* * *

This Privacy Policy was last modified and published on May 22, 2018 and will take effect on May 25, 2018.

The previous version of this policy can be viewed here.

Creative Market Labs, Inc. ("Creative Market," "we," or "us") knows that you care how information about you is used and shared. This Privacy Policy explains what information of yours will be collected by Creative Market when you use the Creative Market Service, how the information will be used, and how you can control the collection, correction and/or deletion of information. This Privacy Policy applies to our Service, which includes www.creativemarket.com, and its sub-domains such as pro.creativemarket.com, also referred to as " **Site** ". We will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information we collect by other means (including offline) or from other sources. Capitalized terms that are not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meaning given them in our Terms of Service.

## Information We Collect

**User-Provided Information:** You provide us information about yourself, such as your name, e-mail address, and other personally identifiable information (all referred to as "Personal Information") if you register for a User account with the Service (including by "following," "liking," adding the Creative Market application, linking your account to the Creative Market service, etc., on a third party website or network). If you correspond with us by email, we may retain the content of your email messages, your email address and our responses. We may also retain any messages you send through the Service. You may provide us information in User Content, such as your public profile and comments that you post to the Service.

**Information Collected Through Cookies And Other Technology:** When you visit the Service, we use cookies and related technologies (such as Clear GIFs/Web Beacons) to identify your browser. Please see here for Information About Our Use of Cookies And Similar Technologies.

**Log File Information:** Log file information is automatically reported by your browser each time you access a web page. Please see here for Information About Our Use of Cookies And Similar Technologies.

**Third Party Analytics Services:** Creative Market uses third party analytics services. See here for how Google uses data when you use our Service and how you may opt out (www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/). We also use [LinkedIn Analytics](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy), [Sift](https://sift.com/service-privacy), [Segment](https://segment.com/docs/legal/privacy/), and [New Relic](https://newrelic.com/privacy). Please see here for Information About Our Use of Cookies And Similar Technologies.

**Social Network and Platform Integration.** The Service may be integrated with social media networks and other platforms (e.g., Facebook, Pinterest, and LinkedIn) whereby information may be shared between us and those platforms. For instance, if you interact with our Service through a social media feature such as a plug-in, then you may be granting us on-going access to certain information from that social media account. If you do not want a social media platform to collect or share information about you, please review the privacy policy and privacy settings of the applicable social media property before using such features on our Service. Please see here for Information About Our Use of Cookies And Similar Technologies.

## How We Use Your Information

**We use the Personal Information you submit or that we collect to operate, maintain, and provide to you the features and functionality of the Service.** We use your information in order to (a) provide you with the Service under our agreement with you and (b) where we have a legitimate interest in doing so to optimize the Service we offer and to let you know about our other products, services and promotions.

By providing us with your email address (which includes, but is not limited to linking your account to the Creative Market service on or through a third party website or network such as Facebook), you acknowledge we may use the email address to send you Service-related notices, including any notices required by law, in lieu of communication by postal mail. You also acknowledge that we may send you notifications of activity on the Service to the email address you give us, in accordance with any applicable privacy settings. We may use your email address to send you other messages, such as newsletters, changes to features of the Service, or special offers. If you do not want to receive such email messages, you may opt out or change your preferences in your account settings page. Opting out may prevent you from receiving email messages regarding updates, improvements, or offers. You may not opt out of Service-related e-mails.

Following termination or deactivation of your User account, we may retain your profile information and User Content for a commercially reasonable time for backup, archival, contract performance and enforcement, or audit purposes but for no longer than is necessary and only where the information is accurate and relevant for our use. Furthermore, we may retain and continue to use indefinitely all information (including User Content) contained in your communications to other Users or posted to public or semi-public areas of the Service after termination or deactivation of your User account.

If you choose to use our invitation service to invite a friend to the Service, we will ask you for that person's email address and automatically send an email invitation. We store this information to send this email, to register your friend if your invitation is accepted, and to track the success of our invitation service. Your friend may contact us to request that we remove this information from our database at [privacy@creativemarket.com](mailto:privacy@creativemarket.com).

We may use certain information about you and/or your User Content internally for purposes such as analyzing how the Service is used, diagnosing service or technical problems, maintaining security, and personalizing content.

We use cookies, clear GIFs, and log file information as described here: Information About Our Use of Cookies And Similar Technologies.

## How We Share Your Information

**Personal Information.** We will not rent or sell your Personal Information to others. We may share your Personal Information with third parties (such as hosting providers, payment processors, database providers, customer support providers) for the purpose of providing the Service to you. If we do this, such third parties' will be contractually bound to safeguard your Personal Information. We may store Personal Information in locations outside of our direct control (for instance, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers) on the basis of an agreement to safeguard your information.

As we develop our business, we may buy or sell assets or business offerings. Customer, email, and visitor information is generally one of the transferred business assets in these types of transactions. We may also transfer or assign such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers, or dissolution.

Any Personal Information or content that you voluntarily disclose for posting to the Service, such as content that you "liked", your first and last name or your username, or placed into a collection and User Content, becomes available to the public (and may be searched by search engines), whether or not you are signed into your account. If you remove information that you posted to the Service, copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of the Service, or if other Users have copied or saved that information.

From time to time, we may run contests, special offers, or other events or activities ("Events") on the Service together with a third party partner. If you provide information to such third parties, you acknowledge they may use it for the purpose of that Event and any other use that you approve. We cannot control third parties' use of your information. If you do not want your information to be collected by or shared with a third party, you can choose not to participate in these Events.

Except as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, we will not disclose Personal Information to any third party unless required to do so by law or subpoena or if we believe that such action is necessary to:

(a) conform to the law, comply with legal process served on us or our affiliates, or investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities;

(b) to enforce our Terms of Service, take precautions against liability, to investigate and defend ourselves against any third-party claims or allegations, to assist government enforcement agencies, or to protect the security or integrity of our Site;

(c) support legitimate interests, such as sharing Personal Information with payment processors and third parties who provide fraud detection services; and

(d) to exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Creative Market or Creative Market Labs, our Users or others.

**Payment Services.** We offer Stripe and PayPal integration. All Stripe and PayPal transactions are subject to the respective policies, Stripe Privacy Policy available at <https://stripe.com/ie/privacy> and PayPal Privacy Policy available at <https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full>. We do not control Stripe or PayPal's use of the data it collects.

**Non-Personal Information.** We may share non-personally identifiable information (such as anonymous usage data, referring/exit pges and URLs, platform types, number of clicks, etc.) with interested third parties to help them understand the usage patterns for certain Creative Market services.

**Targeting and Marketing.** Although we do not serve third-party advertising on our Site, we do work with third-parties to target advertising for our Site on the third-party websites. These cookies record your visit to our Site, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make our Site more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose. Please see here for Information About Our Use of Cookies And Similar Technologies.

## Data Transfers outside the EEA

If you are resident in the European Union, please note that as we are located in the United States, when you provide us with your Personal Information we will process it in countries outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"), such as the United States, which may not provide the same level of data protection as in your jurisdiction. This is necessary in order to perform our services. Regardless of where your Personal Information is located, we will adopt measures to protect your Personal Information as set out below.

## How We Protect Your Information

We care about the integrity and security of your Personal Information and implement appropriate technical and organisation security measures to safeguard your Personal Information. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to Creative Market or guarantee that your information on the Service may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. Your privacy settings may also be affected by changes to the functionality of Creative Market's distributors, such as social networks. We are not responsible for the functionality or security measures of any third party.

To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps (such as requesting a unique password) to verify your identity before granting you access to your account. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information, and for controlling access to your email communications from Creative Market, at all times.

## Compromise of Personal Information

In the event that Personal Information is compromised as a result of a breach of security, we will promptly notify those persons whose Personal Information has been compromised, in accordance with the notification procedures set forth in this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise required by applicable law.

**"Do Not Track" Signals.** Your browser settings may allow you to automatically transmit a "do not track" signal to websites and online services you visit. At this time there is no consensus among industry participants as to the meaning of "do not track" in this context. Like many other websites, the Sites are not configured to respond to "do not track" signals from browsers. [Click here to learn more about "do not track" signals](https://allaboutdnt.com/).

## Your Choices About Your Information

**All Users**

  * Decline to Submit Information. You may, of course, decline to submit Personal Information through the Service, in which case Creative Market may not be able to provide certain services to you.
  * Update Account Information. You may update or correct your account information and email preferences at any time by logging in to your account settings page. You can also exercise any of your rights by contacting us directly at [privacy@creativemarket.com](mailto:privacy@creativemarket.com).
  * Unsubscribe from emails. To unsubscribe from a particular newsletter, click the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of that email newsletter. When we send newsletters to subscribers we may allow advertisers or partners to include messages in those newsletters, or we may send dedicated newsletters and marketing messages on behalf of those advertisers or partners. We may disclose your opt-out choices to third parties so that they can honor your preferences in accordance with applicable laws.
  * Blocking cookies. Certain browsers may be configured to notify you when you receive cookies, or allow you to restrict or disable certain cookies. If you choose to disable cookies, however, that could affect certain features of the Service that use cookies to enhance their functionality. Please see here for Information About Our Use of Cookies And Similar Technologies.
  * Disabling local shared objects (e.g., Flash cookies). We may use other kinds of local storage that function similarly, but are stored in different parts of your computer from ordinary browser cookies, including Flash cookies placed on your device or web browser via the Adobe flash plug-in. Your browser may allow you to disable its HTML5 local storage or delete information contained in its HTML5 local storage. Click here for further details about deleting information contained in "local shared objects" or adjusting related preferences. Please see here for Information About Our Use of Cookies And Similar Technologies.
  * Options concerning third-party ad networks. For more information about third-party ad networks and services that use these technologies, you can visit www.aboutads.info and click here to opt out or to learn more about your options. You also may visit the NAI's site for additional options on how to opt out of interest-based advertising. Please see here for Information About Our Use of Cookies And Similar Technologies.

**California Residents.** Subject to certain limits, under California law California residents may ask us to provide them with a list of the categories of Personal Information that we have disclosed to third parties for those third parties' direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year, as well as the identity of those third parties. California residents may contact us as specified in the Contact Us section below to make a request for this information.

**EEA Residents.** If you are located in the EEA, or if otherwise required by applicable law, you also have the following rights in relation to your information:

  * **Inspection and access:** you can request from us a summary and a copy of any Personal Information we hold about you;
  * **Correction/addition/removal:** where you believe your information is inaccurate or incomplete, you are entitled to request us to correct, amend or delete it;
  * **Portability:** you may request that we send you any Personal Information that you have provided to us or ask that we send this information to a third party;
  * **Objection:** you may object to us using your Personal Information where we use it based on our legitimate interests to do so;
  * **Restriction:** you may request that we restrict the processing of your information where you believe it is inaccurate, our processing is unlawful, you believe we no longer need the information or if you have objected to our use of it; and
  * **Automated Decision Making:** where we undertake automated decision making (including profiling), which significantly affects you, you are entitled to object to such decision-making.

You always have the right to lodge a complaint with the relevant supervisory authority for data protection in your jurisdiction.

## Children's Privacy

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, we do not knowingly collect or solicit Personal Information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register as Members. If you are under 13, please do not send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address. No one under age 13 is allowed to provide any Personal Information to or on Creative Market. In the event that we learn that we have collected Personal Information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [privacy@creativemarket.com](mailto:privacy@creativemarket.com).

## Links to Other Web Sites

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from the Service, nor the information or content contained therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from the Service to another website, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other website, including those that have a link on our website, is subject to that website's own rules and policies. Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding.

## Notification Procedures

It is our policy to provide notifications, whether such notifications are required by law or are for marketing or other business related purposes, to you via email notice, written or hard copy notice, or through conspicuous posting of such notice on the Service, as determined by us in our sole discretion. We reserve the right to determine the form and means of providing notifications to you, provided that you may opt out of certain means of notification as described in this Privacy Policy.

## Changes to Our Privacy Policy

We may update its Privacy Policy from time to time, and so you should review this Policy periodically. When we change the policy in a material way, we will update the 'last modified' date at the top of this Privacy Policy. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

## Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this Site, or your dealings with this website, please contact us at [privacy@creativemarket.com](mailto:privacy@creativemarket.com), or send mail to:

Creative Market Labs, Inc.  
600 Congress Ave, 14th Floor  
Austin, TX 78701

VeraSafe has been appointed as Creative Market's representative in the European Union for data protection matters, pursuant to Article 27 of the General Data Protection Regulation of the European Union. VeraSafe can be contacted, in addition to Creative Market's contact information above, **only** on matters related to the processing of personal data. To make such an inquiry, please contact VeraSafe using this contact form: <https://www.verasafe.com/privacy-services/contact-article-27-representative>

Alternatively, VeraSafe can be contacted at:

VeraSafe Czech Republic s.r.o  
Klimentská 46  
Prague 1, 11002  
Czech Republic

VeraSafe Ireland Ltd  
Unit 3D North Point House  
North Point Business Park  
New Mallow Road  
Cork T23AT2P  
Ireland
